dysregulated map case signaling has been
implicated in a wide range of cancers
and occurs via multiple mechanisms
including activation of receptors and
activating chaos and b-raf mutations
these may lead to increased or
uncontrolled cell proliferation
resistance to a potato sis program cell
death and resistance to chemotherapy
radiotherapy and targeted therapies a
vast array of growth factors exert their
effects by the recruitment and
activation of signaling molecules of
this pathway which include wrath wrath
mech and erk also known as map cake map
case signaling is activated through
binding of a growth factor to the
extracellular domain of the tyrosine
kinase receptor signaling molecules grb2
and sauce our next recruited to the
internal docking site resulting in rass
activation of the membrane the
efficiency and duration of signal
transmission is regulated by the
scaffolding protein kinase suppressor of
rass ksr Raz triggers of phosphorylation
cascade involving wrath mech and erk
proteins leading to erk activation and
translocation to the nucleus once in the
nucleus Ark activates several
transcription factors that mediate gene
expression target genes thus activated
by map case signaling contribute to
higher proliferation and survival
Genentech by oncology is researching new
ways to inhibit map k pathway signaling