Sharon was given a few months to live if
her cancer wasn't treated I was
diagnosed with advanced non-small-cell
lung cancer which I thought meant chemo
but a biomarker test showed I had high
levels of PDL one which meant I could
start with a different treatment one
year later she's here with her family a
true story with key Trudeau I'm Kate
Rita my scan started showing good news
in a clinical study key true to offer
patients a longer life than chemotherapy
and with high levels of PDL one it could
be your first treatment instead of
chemotherapy key tutors for adults with
non-small-cell lung cancer that has
spread who test positive for PDL 1 and
whose tumors do not have an abnormal
EGFR or algae teach you to help your
immune system fight cancer T true that
can cause your immune system to attack
normal organs and tissues in your body
and affect how they work and may be
serious and lead to death see your
doctor right away if you experience new
or worsening cough chest pain shortness
of breath diarrhea severe stomach pain
or tenderness nausea or vomiting rapid
heartbeat increased hunger or thirst
constipation dizziness or fainting
changes in urine changes in eyesight
muscle pain or weakness joint pain rash
itching or flushing as this may keep
these problems from becoming more
serious these are not all the possible
side effects of katroo de tell your
doctor about all your medical conditions
including immune system problems or if
you've had an organ transplant or lung
reading or liver problems each day now
it's a gift
a chance for a longer life it's true
katroo de from Merck ask your doctor
about katroo de