<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><timedtext format="3">
<body>
<p t="1300" d="7000"> </p>
<p t="8300" d="3230">Hi. It&#39;s Mr. Andersen. Over a million people
every year develop cancer. There are over</p>
<p t="11530" d="4980">a hundred different types of cancer. But many
people don&#39;t really know what is cancer? And</p>
<p t="16510" d="4499">the answer to that question is very simple.
If we look at a normal cell, on the inside</p>
<p t="21009" d="5461">of the cell is the nuclei. And that contains
DNA. And the DNA contains genes that control</p>
<p t="26470" d="4029">the actions of the cell. And one of those
important actions is how a cell makes a copy</p>
<p t="30499" d="4321">of itself. How it goes through what we call
the cell cycle. And so if you take a normal</p>
<p t="34820" d="4809">cell and put it in culture it will simply
make a copy of itself. And if there&#39;s room</p>
<p t="39629" d="3610">those cells will make copies of themselves
and they&#39;ll keep doing that until they fill</p>
<p t="43239" d="5340">up that area. And if one of these cells dies
then an adjacent cell is going to jump into</p>
<p t="48579" d="4841">that cell cycle and it&#39;s going to fill that
hole. And so that&#39;s how you went from a zygote</p>
<p t="53420" d="4750">to the trillions of cells that are inside
your body. And that&#39;s also how you replace</p>
<p t="58170" d="4700">cells. And so your skin is constantly losing
cells off the surface. But we&#39;re creating</p>
<p t="62870" d="6100">cells underneath that. And so the cause of
all cancers is the same. There is going to</p>
<p t="68970" d="5730">be damage to the DNA. And so that DNA is made
up of what are called nucleotides. And there</p>
<p t="74700" d="4350">are tons of genes in there that are controlling
this cell cycle. When a cell should make a</p>
<p t="79050" d="5200">copy of itself and when it should stop dividing.
And so a mutation is simply damage to that</p>
<p t="84250" d="5260">DNA. Now it could just occur spontaneously.
If we all live long enough we&#39;re all going</p>
<p t="89510" d="4140">to develop cancer because these mutations
are going to start to accrue during our life</p>
<p t="93650" d="5550">time. But we can also increase the rate of
those mutations using the environment. And</p>
<p t="99200" d="4220">so for example if we smoke cigarettes that
could cause mutations to the DNA. Increases</p>
<p t="103420" d="6520">in UV radiation. We&#39;re finding decreases in
exercise. Increases in certain types of diet</p>
<p t="109940" d="5510">can cause mutations. And that can cause problems
in the cell cycle. And so let&#39;s say we get</p>
<p t="115450" d="4080">a mutation in this cell right here. There
are going to be genes within that cell that</p>
<p t="119530" d="3780">sense something is wrong. And lots of times
it will undergo apoptosis where that cell</p>
<p t="123310" d="6440">dies and another cell moves inside. But during
our lifetime we start to accrue more and more</p>
<p t="129750" d="4600">mutations. And eventually enough mutations
build in one of those cells and it becomes</p>
<p t="134350" d="5200">not a normal cell but a cancerous cell. And
this takes a long time for that to occur.</p>
<p t="139550" d="4870">And so this is a pretty awful graph. This
is the increase in the popularity of cigarettes.</p>
<p t="144420" d="5140">And so this is the number of cigarette smoking
per person per year. And so as they were doing</p>
<p t="149560" d="4520">that they were increasing the mutations inside
their body. And we can look decades later,</p>
<p t="154080" d="6120">we see the causation. We can see an increase
in lung cancer in men as well. And so as we</p>
<p t="160200" d="4540">make those mistakes in our cell we form these
cancerous cells. Now what does a cancerous</p>
<p t="164740" d="4410">cell do? It doesn&#39;t matter that there are
cells around it. It is simply going to divide</p>
<p t="169150" d="5370">and divide and divide. Over and over and over
again. And eventually what you create is a</p>
<p t="174520" d="5670">tumor. Now there are two types of tumor. If
those cells are restricted to that one area</p>
<p t="180190" d="5860">and stay within a membrane we call those benign
tumors. And that&#39;s not cancer. But if there</p>
<p t="186050" d="4130">is no restriction to that area it becomes
what&#39;s called a malignant tumor. And that&#39;s</p>
<p t="190180" d="5110">really a definition of what cancer is. It&#39;s
when we have these uncontrolled cell growth</p>
<p t="195290" d="5169">and those cells show uncontrolled cell growth
spread throughout our body. And so this is</p>
<p t="200459" d="5581">a video of some cancerous cells. And so instead
of just growing and doing the jobs of the</p>
<p t="206040" d="4320">cell, you can see they are kind of misshapen.
And all they do is make copies of themselves</p>
<p t="210360" d="3570">and copies of themselves over and over and
over again. That&#39;s where all of the energy</p>
<p t="213930" d="5000">is going. Now if that was restricted to one
area it wouldn&#39;t be as big a deal. But they</p>
<p t="218930" d="4450">can move to different areas of the body. And
so if we have a tumor right here, it can start</p>
<p t="223380" d="3910">to invade the tissues around it. And so that
tumor can not only get larger, but it can</p>
<p t="227290" d="5559">move into new areas. And if that tumor gets
into the lymphatic system or the circulatory</p>
<p t="232849" d="4801">system, it can move around our body and it
can settle somewhere else. And so that&#39;s the</p>
<p t="237650" d="5089">problem with a malignant tumor. And so we
name cancers based on the tissues and the</p>
<p t="242739" d="3811">organs that they infect. So this would be
lung cancer. But we could also have colon</p>
<p t="246550" d="4870">cancer. Or maybe pancreatic cancer or breast
cancer. It&#39;s basically named on the tissue</p>
<p t="251420" d="4969">of where it is. Now each of those cancers,
even though the cause is the same, damage</p>
<p t="256389" d="5280">to the DNA which produces uncontrolled cell
growth, the way they manifest the disease</p>
<p t="261669" d="3601">is going to be totally different. And so if
you look at this x-ray we can see that this</p>
<p t="265270" d="4269">is somebody who has lung cancer. And there&#39;s
going to be a tumor right there. And what</p>
<p t="269539" d="5421">we&#39;re finding is not only are all these different
types cancer different, but each of those</p>
<p t="274960" d="4949">individual tumors are different. And between
two people those tumors are going to be different.</p>
<p t="279909" d="3660">And even within the cells of the tumor they&#39;re
going to be different. And so what does that</p>
<p t="283569" d="5011">mean? Well even though we might treat one
tumor, we&#39;re going to find that within that</p>
<p t="288580" d="4079">tumor there are going to be different cells.
Each of those have different genetic problems.</p>
<p t="292659" d="5230">And so we could treat most of the tumor, remove
most of it, but it is going to come back eventually</p>
<p t="297889" d="5691">over time. And so what do we have for treatments?
And so since cancer is uncontrolled cell growth</p>
<p t="303580" d="4190">we want to find those cells and quickly as
we can. And so screening is the most important</p>
<p t="307770" d="4560">thing. Once we find that cancer has developed
and we find that tumor, the first thing that</p>
<p t="312330" d="4750">we want to do is we want to remove that. And
so surgery is generally what happens next.</p>
<p t="317080" d="4869">We remove that tumor. We also use radiation.
In other words we&#39;re not going to be able</p>
<p t="321949" d="4150">to remove all of those cell. There are going
to be extraneous cells around it. And so we</p>
<p t="326099" d="5190">can target this with ionizing radiation. And
we can kill all those cells. Now this has</p>
<p t="331289" d="4960">dangers as well. And so we try to restrict
that to that one area. But it can cause damage</p>
<p t="336249" d="4720">to the cells around it. And then often times
we&#39;ll use chemotherapy. Now what is chemotherapy</p>
<p t="340969" d="4750">doing? It&#39;s going throughout your whole body.
And it is targeting cells that are actively</p>
<p t="345719" d="4440">dividing. Cells that are going through this
cell cycle. And so that&#39;s why it affects,</p>
<p t="350159" d="3850">for example, you get a lot of nausea. Because
it&#39;s affecting those cells in your digestive</p>
<p t="354009" d="4310">tract. Or you lose your hair because it is
affecting those cells that are quickly making,</p>
<p t="358319" d="4590">that are constantly making new hair. And so
with all of these we&#39;re getting better and</p>
<p t="362909" d="6180">better at treating cancer. What&#39;s the future
hold? Well we&#39;re really just treating just</p>
<p t="369089" d="4630">all cancers with these three methods the same.
And so what we&#39;ll see is if we can get into</p>
<p t="373719" d="4750">the genetics and we start to understand how
each of those cancers are different then we</p>
<p t="378469" d="4280">can start to target them. And so one of the
breakthroughs was Gleevec which is one of</p>
<p t="382749" d="5540">these first drugs that&#39;s targeting a specific
type of leukemia. And it was affecting a specific</p>
<p t="388289" d="5201">machinery within that cell. And so again,
the more we understand about cancer we find</p>
<p t="393490" d="4199">that they are all the same but the causes
are going to be different. And so what is</p>
<p t="397689" d="7000">cancer? It&#39;s simply uncontrolled cell growth.
And I hope that was helpful.</p>
</body>
</timedtext>
