okay so now we should be recording so
what you do is you've got your SRT file
uploaded and you go to the wrench and
you choose to clear the timing so what
that's going to do is it's going to
preserve all the little bits of text but
it's going to erase how they're timed so
I'm going to clear the timing you're
sure you want to do this yep I want to
do that so now you see it's a little
different color it's kind of
cream-colored instead of light and now
what it's going to do is it's going to
take those it's going to take those
subtitles that are existing and every
time I press the down arrow it's going
to start a new one so the trick is and
it took me a time going through it to
get it but here's the subtitle on the
screen and what I'm watching for is I'm
listening for him to say this last word
and when he says that last word I hit
the down arrow and that will start then
that will pull the next that will end
this one and start the next one does
that make sense
so listen to what I'm when I'm watching
and that makes sense I'm doing it caused
by the ingestion
pericardial mesothelioma is so rarest
form of mesothelioma that is frequently
found in conjunction with Charlie
superior the pericardium covers the
heart and act as a protective barrier
for not only a hundred and fifty cases
have ever been reported and people a
voice assembly only lightly backyards
posterior cervical removal of the
pericardium is referred to as the
lessons constrictions on the heart
little mr. Feeley oma being the most
common makes up 75% of all mesothelioma
cases it is a tumor that affects the
mesothelium covering that protects a lot
even though it is the most common state
to be Sicilian life and it's still rare
and is often misdiagnosed several lung
diseases that this one cancer high on
the movie
we Sophie Leona and it's symptoms often
do not reveal themselves until forty
years after exposure to asbestos if you
think you or individuals you know may
have mesothelioma please call one eight
hundred nine or nine six three seven six
if you or someone you know is interested
in our clinical trial for more
information about the symptoms of all
three types of mesothelioma or some
specific answers to a particular
situation please call a toll-free number
to the mesothelioma
Research Foundation of America one eight
hundred nine oh nine
Lisa that's one eight hundred nine oh
nine six three seven six or visit our
central website at WWE so RFA org
feel free to ask about a clinical trial
led by doctor forecast skill
so that makes sense how that went so now
there's timings but you noticed in the
beginning it didn't quite it didn't
start like I was expecting it to start
right so you can still go back now and
chain so this should be here right
cancer tree disease so these first few
were messed up and why I didn't why it
did that that way I don't know but it
got better pretty quick but so now again
I'm looking at the layer of tissue that
covers many of the body's organs the
heart that's I must have been
so now we got into the rhythm and we're
and we're good so now the timings are
now the timings are right and what you
can do is now that we're making the
second pass now you can actually make
the corrections in the in the English if
it's if it's bad and you can fix the
timings if you notice something doesn't
start right but I know when we've done
in the past those timings were all off
right you'd have to slide them around
for everything and you were always
trying to get ahead of it but it would
never let you so you're always having to
pull everything back and it was a it was
a tremendous pain so clearing the
timings and then just retiming it I
think is the best probably the best way
to start it's horrible if it's a if it's
a half an hour video it means you sit
there for half an hour listening to it
and hitting down every time it or any
time it does it but it is the best way I
mean it'll take longer than half an hour
to fix the timings if they're off and
it's better to start with something than
starting with nothing so it's kind of a
long process but it's doing it this way
I think it's not as long as it would be
if you do it the other way
does that make sense so in a closed the
recording oh yeah yeah that's good so
that I guess